{
    "id": "1efdf904158149e8b5a180b0febf3ad1",
    "title": "General Grammar Exercise (Gap Filling)",
    "questions": [
        {
            "question": "…………………………. you start now, you will be late for the party.",
            "description": "Unless is similar to if not.",
            "answers": [
                "If",
                "Without",
                "Unless"
            ],
            "correct": 2,
            "id": "6965052057b14173a0c7afc4773089ca"
        },
        {
            "question": "He ………………………….. to be an actor.",
            "description": "The present perfect is more common with always, ever, never etc.",
            "answers": [
                "always wanted",
                "is always wanting",
                "has always wanted"
            ],
            "correct": 2,
            "id": "e7061d070aae4d6fa23ac423968c4efe"
        },
        {
            "question": "She has been absent ………………………. Monday.",
            "description": "Since indicates the starting point.",
            "answers": [
                "for",
                "from",
                "since"
            ],
            "correct": 2,
            "id": "afae89ddeb7b44b3ad6f25747af0b950"
        },
        {
            "question": "They accused me ………………………… their conversation.",
            "description": "",
            "answers": [
                "to overhear",
                "of overhearing",
                "of overhear"
            ],
            "correct": 1,
            "id": "22490a8d98c74da6a4030098a86b1e90"
        },
        {
            "question": "She asked me if I ……………………….. a drink.",
            "description": "When the main verb is in the past tense, use a past tense in the subordinate clause as well. ",
            "answers": [
                "want",
                "wanted",
                "had wanted"
            ],
            "correct": 1,
            "id": "be0561502f8e414eb2c709e6b952accd"
        },
        {
            "question": "I ………………………….. TV at 8 o’clock yesterday evening.",
            "description": "Use the past continuous to say that an activity was in progress at a particular point of time in the past. ",
            "answers": [
                "was watching",
                "watched",
                "had watched"
            ],
            "correct": 0,
            "id": "b6b363c1f4694757858f3430a1539bf5"
        },
        {
            "question": "Ever since she returned to her native place she …………………………. Jobless.",
            "description": "The present perfect is used to indicate time up to now.",
            "answers": [
                "was",
                "is",
                "has been"
            ],
            "correct": 2,
            "id": "832a147215924edf96c5634278cae352"
        },
        {
            "question": "I do not ………………………… his activities.",
            "description": "",
            "answers": [
                "approve to",
                "approve with",
                "approve of"
            ],
            "correct": 2,
            "id": "4ea741fa32514a8f89febc6e5fdf50b8"
        },
        {
            "question": "I will give him the message as soon as he ……………………………..",
            "description": "When the main verb is in the future tense, use a present tense in the subordinate clause to refer to future time.",
            "answers": [
                "arrive",
                "arrives",
                "will arrive",
                "arrived"
            ],
            "correct": 1,
            "id": "2e34b8a4a2c04ac49401cc7007445165"
        },
        {
            "question": "If you ………………………… a little louder, I could hear you properly.",
            "description": "",
            "answers": [
                "speak",
                "spoke",
                "had spoken"
            ],
            "correct": 1,
            "id": "b8885cd0af4c4227a060c58ded32c0cf"
        },
        {
            "question": "My car is faster than …………………………….",
            "description": "Yours means the same as your car.",
            "answers": [
                "you",
                "your",
                "yours"
            ],
            "correct": 2,
            "id": "5e31c3f86f854522ab02c5fe94ad818e"
        },
        {
            "question": "You need not ............................... the plants.",
            "description": "When need is an auxiliary verb, it is followed by an infinitive without to.",
            "answers": [
                "water",
                "to water"
            ],
            "correct": 0,
            "id": "022fbd3e05e04238a4bcbbb8d79a9daa"
        }
    ]
}